## **Thor Wessel Lindberg**

Reykjavík, Iceland thor@lindberg.is

lindberg.is

linkedin.com/in/thorlindberg



M.Sc. IT specialized in UX Design, with a cross-disciplinary background in medical science, information technology and user-centred design. Through working as a Consultant I have become versed in managing and mediating clients, as I collaborated with multi-national teams on both a Javabased backend and React Native frontend software.

In my spare time I enjoy building software, experimenting with new technologies, and traveling throughout the United States to network with others in the technology sector.

# **Experience**

Netcompany

08/2022 - 12/2023

### **IT Consultant**

- · Responsible for client contact, mediating meetings, status reporting, managing project timeline and tasks.
- · Analyzed and documented existing business processes on 2 projects for 2 clients.
- · Analyzed IT-infrastructure and digital transformation strategy on 2 projects for 2 clients.
- · Contributed to source code for Java-based backend.
- · Contributed to source code optimization and adding features to React Native frontend application.

National Special Crime Unit

10/2021 - 07/2022

# **IT-Administrative Student**

- · Managed users of webportal and provided direct support for reporting suspicion of financial crime.
- · Authored software documentation and website

IT University of Copenhagen

08/2021 - 06/2022

### **Teaching Assistant**

· Assisted with teaching courses in Python, JavaScript with MQTT, and UX Design specialization.

Domino's Pizza

08/2021 - 01/2022

### **Shift Leader**

· Responsible for closing store, delegating work, managing cash, and primary pizza baker.

### Education

IT University of Copenhagen

08/2020 - 06/2022

### Master of Science in Digital Design (cand.it)

Thesis: Type-Extensible Objection Notation (TXON)

· Explorative design for embedding typeset objects within constraints of the JSON format.

#### Relevant courses:

· Mobile app development with Expo and React Native, UX Design, Advanced Design Processes.

Copenhagen University

08/2017 - 07/2020

### Bachelor of Science in Health Informatics (bach.sund.it)

Thesis: Tools for caretakers of stroke victims

· Qualitative analysis to determine potential low-cost digital solutions for caretakers of stroke victims, within economic constraints of the Danish healthcare system.

#### Relevant courses:

· Statistics, Mathematical Modelling, Medical Image Analysis, IT Security, Interaction Design, Programming for Biosciences, Human Anatomy and Physiology.

### Certificates

Google

03/2024 - Now

Google UX Design

University of California, San Diego

03/2024 - Now

## **Data Structures and Algorithms**

### **Skills**

React, React Native, JavaScript, TypeScript, Swift, SwiftUI, UIKit, Java, MATLAB, Azure, Git

Python, NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Visual Basic for Applications (VBA), Excel macros

Figma, components, variants, interactive flows, auto layout

Fluent in English and Danish. Beginner at Icelandic

## **Published**

# Áfangastaður - Explore Iceland

apps.apple.com/app/id6466740299